Guide to the Residential Child Care Project records, 1981-1997.
Residential Child Care Project records, 1981-1997.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Residential Child Care Project records, 1981-1997.
23-13-3296
Residential Child Care Project.
4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, training manuals, brochures, and symposium material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports, training manuals, brochures, and symposium material concerning the Residential Child Care Project in the Family Life Development Center at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, reports, training manuals, brochures, and symposium material concerning the Residential Child Care Project in the Family Life Development Center at Cornell University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Residential Child Care Project.; New York State College of Human Ecology. Family Life Development Center.
Subjects:
Child care.; Family life education--United States.; Parent and child.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- SUNY Buffalo Evaluation Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- SUNY Buffalo Follow-Up Report, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- SUNY Buffalo Evaluation Reports-January, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- SUNY Buffalo Evaluation Reports-Feb -March, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- SUNY Buffalo Evaluation Reports-April-June, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- SUNY Buffalo Evaluation Reports-July-September, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Early TCI Pre and Post and Demo-1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Basic - Module one - Objectives Checklist (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Evaluation of the Early March Supervisors Training New York City (Box 1, Folder 6)
- CPS Basic Residency Training - Module 3 assessment Train-the-Trainer 1983 - Instructors Manual Lesson Plan - Module 1 - Day 1 - Pre Investigation and Investigation (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Supervisor Case Management - Cycle II - Day 1 - June 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Module III - Dynamics and Assessment (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Module IV - Case Management (Box 1, Folder 8)
- CDHS - SUNY Buffalo - Training followup 10/94-7/95 Grant 6056-Q, Quarters 1-3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- CWI - Outcomes and Abilities for Outcome Based Training - 1/96 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CWI - Summary of Observations from Regional Focus Groups - Outcome Based Training - 1/96 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- I CA/N MAKE A DIFFERENCE Symposium Brochure - 12/88 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- SUNY Buffalo - Final Evaluation Report Child Protective Services Basic Residency Training, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- SUNY Buffalo - Final Evaluation Report Child Protective Services Basic Residency Training, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI Program Brochure, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI Program Brochure, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI Program Brochure, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI Program Brochure, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI Program Brochure, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI Program Brochure, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI Announcement of Training Programs, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI CPS Announcement of Programs, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI CPS Announcement, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI RCCP Announcement, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI CPS Announcement, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI RCCP Announcement, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Risk Assessment Computer Based Training Program Instructional Guide (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Preliminary Report on the Evaluation of Training: New York State Risk Assessment and Services Planning Model Direct Training for DSS District Staff 3/1/92-7/1/92, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI - Risk Assessment Report - 10/1/92-12/31/92 Contract #: C-005636, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CPSTI - Risk Assessment Report - 4/1/93-6/30/93 Contract #: C-005636, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Risk Assessment Training Report - December 1993, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- CPSTI - Risk Assessment Report Suffolk County 1/94-3/94 Contract #: C-005636, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- CPSTI Final Risk Assessment Program Report - October 1992 - March 1994 Contract #: C-005636, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- CPSTI - Risk Assessment Report Warren, Nassau, Chenango/Tiogo Counties 4/94-5/94 Contract #: C-006023, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- CPSTI - Quarterly Risk Report 4/1/94-6/30/94 Contract #: C-006023, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- CPSTI - Quarterly Risk Report 7/1/94-9/30/94 Contract #: C-006023, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- CPSTI - Annual Report for Risk Assessment 10/1/93-9/30/94 Contract #: C-006023, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Evaluation Report of the Basic Training of the CPSTI - Contract #: C162341, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CPSTI Third Quarterly and Preliminary Final Report Contract #: C165902 Contract Year 1981-82, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CPSTI Evaluation Report of the Basic Training of the CPSTI Contract #: C165902 1981-82 Final Report + Addendum Report, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CPSTI 1981-82 Final Report Contract #: C165902, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CPSTI Overview and Final Report of the CPSTI Contract #: C165902 Contract Year 1981-82, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CPSTI First Quarterly Report of the CPSTI Contract #: C165902 Contract Year 1982-83, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CPSTI Second Trimester Report of the CPSTI Contract Year 1982-83, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CPSTI Final Report 1982-83, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- CPSTI Second Quarterly Report 1/1/83-3/31/84 Contract #: C169502 Amendment A, 1984 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Third Quarterly Report 4/1/84-6/30/84 Contract #: C169502 Amendment A, 1984 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Fourth Quarterly Report 7/1/84-9/30/84 Contract #: C169502 Amendment A, 1984 (Box 2)
- Contract Extension Report 10/1/84-12/31/84 Contract #: C169502 Amendment A, 1984 (Box 2)
- Final Report 1983-84 Contract #: C169502 Amendment A, 1983-84 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Final Report 1984-85 Contract #: C000793, 1984-85 (Box 2)
- CPSTI 1985-86 Annual Evaluation Report Contract # C001385 Amendment 1986, 1985-86 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 1/1/86-3/31/86 Contract # C000793, 1986 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 4/1/86-6/30/86 Contract # C000793, 1986 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 7/1/86-9/30/86 Contract # C000793, 1986 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Final Report 10/1/85-1/31/87 Contract # C001793385 Amendment 1986, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 10/1/86-12/31/86 Contract # C001385 Amendment 1986, 1986 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 1/1/87-3/31/87 Contract # C001385 Amendment 1986, 1987 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 4/1/87-6/30/87 Contract # C001385 Amendment 1986, 1987 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 10/1/87-12/31/87 Contract # C001385 Amendment 1986, 1987 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 1/1/88-3/31/88 Contract # C-002163, 1988 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Final Program Report for the Period 10/1/86 - 3/31/88 Contract # C-002163 Amendment 2, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 4/1/88-6/30/88 Contract # C-002163, 1988 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 7/1/88-9/30/88 Contract # C-002163, 1988 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 10/1/88-12/31/88 Contract # C-002163, 1988 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 1/1/89-3/31/89 Contract # C-002163, 1989 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Final Program Report for the Period 4/1/88-3/31/89 Contract # C-002163 Amendment 2, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 4/1/89-6/30/89 Contract # C-002163, 1989 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 7/1/89-9/30/89 Contract # C-002163, 1989 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 10/1/89-12/31/89 Contract # C-002163, 1989 (Box 2)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 1/1/90-3/31/90 Contract # C-002163, 1990 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Final Program Report for the Period 4/1/89-3/31/90 Contract # C-002163, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 4/1/90-6/30/90 Contract # C-002163, 1990 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 7/1/90-9/30/90 Contract # C-002163, 1990 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 10/1/90-12/31/90 Contract # C-002163, 1990 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 1/1/91-3/31/91 Contract # C-002163, 1991 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 4/1/91-6/30/91 Contract # C-002163, 1991 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Final Program Report for the Period 4/1/90-6/30/91 Contract # C-002163, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Final Program Report for the Period 4/1/90-6/30/91 and Extension Period 4/1/91-12/31/91 Contract # C-002163, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 7/1/91-9/30/91 Contract # C-002163, 1991 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 10/1/91-12/31/91 Contract # C-002163, 1991 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 1/1/92-3/31/92 Contract # C-002163, 1992 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 4/1/92-6/30/92 Contract # C-002163, 1992 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 7/1/92-9/30/92 Contract # C-004148, 1992 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Extension Report 10/1/92-12/31/92 Contract # C-004148, 1992 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Extension Report 1/1/93-3/31/93 Contract # C-004148, 1993 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Final Program Report for the Period 7/1/91-3/31/93 Contract # C-004148, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 10/1/92-12/31/92 Contract # C-005636, 1992 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 1/1/93-3/31/93 Contract # C-005636, 1993 (Box 3)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 4/1/93-6/30/93 Contract # C-005636, 1993 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 7/1/93-9/30/93 Contract # C-005636, 1993 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Extension Report 10/1/93-12/31/93 Contract # C-005636, 1993 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Extension Report 1/1/94-3/31/94 Contract # C-005636, 1994 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Final Program Report for the Period 10/92-3/94 Contract # C-005636, 1992-1994 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 10/1/93-12/31/93 Contract # C-006023, 1993 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 1/1/94-3/31/94 Contract # C-006023, 1994 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 4/1/94-6/30/94 Contract # C-006023, 1994 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Quarterly Report 7/1/94-9/30/94 Contract # C-006023, 1994 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Annual Report 10/1/93-9/30/94 Contract # C-006023, 1994 (Box 4)
- CPSTI CPS Core Training SCDF:34 1994-95, 1994-1995 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 1st Quarter Report 10/1/94-12/31/94 Contract # 006024, 1994 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 2nd Quarter Report 1/1/95-3/31/95 Contract # 006024, 1995 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 3rd Quarter Report 4/1/95-6/30/95 MOA 26915/CPSTI 1994-1995, 1995 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 4th Quarter Report 7/1/95-9/30/95 MOA 0489 (OSP # 26915)/CPSTI 1994-1995, 1995 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Annual Report 10/1/94-9/30/95 MOA 0489 (OSP #26915)/CPSTI 1994-1995, 1994-1995 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 1st Quarter Report 10/1/95-12/31/95 MOA (OSP #29112)/CPSTI 1995-1996, 1995 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 2nd Quarter Report 1/1/96-3/31/96 MOA 5060 (OSP #29112)/CPSTI 1995-1996, 1996 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 3rd Quarter Report 4/1/96-6/30/96 MOA 5060 (OSP #29112)/CPSTI 1995-1996, 1996 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 4th Quarter Report 7/1/96-9/30/96 MOA 5060 (OSP #29112)/CPSTI 1995-1996, 1996 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Annual Report 10/1/95-9/30/96 MOA 5060 (OSP #29112)/CPSTI 1995-1996, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 1st Quarter Report 10/1/96-12/31/96 MOU# 0489 (OSP #31252), 1996 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 2nd Quarter Report 1/1/97-3/31/97 MOU# 0489 (OSP # 31252), 1997 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 3rd Quarter Report 4/1/97-6/30/97 MOU# 0489 (OSP #31252), 1997 (Box 4)
- CPSTI 4th Quarter Report 7/1/97-9/30/97 MOU# 0489 (OSP #31252), 1997 (Box 4)
- CPSTI Contract Report 10/1/97-12/31/97 MOA#: COR-9501 (OCT-DEC 1997), 1997 (Box 4)
- DFY Information for Michigan and Adrian Training School, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Institutional Abuse Resources, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Correspondence with University of Texas at Austin, 3/27/81, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- ERIC Query: Child Abuse or Neglected Children, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Colorado Regulations, Division of Youth Services, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Response to Agencywide Crisis: A Model for Administrative Action by Floyd J.Alwon, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- In the Matter of Pedro Montez, New York State Commission on Quality of Care, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Organizational Culture: Its Pivotal Role in Residential Treatment Programs by Donald. A. Sawyer and David Woodlock, Presented at a Conference in Monticello, New York, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- The Abused Child, Clinical Symposia, CIBA, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Shedding the Threat of Institutional Abuse, Newsletter of the Region III: Child Abuse and Neglect Resource Center, Volume 5, Number 1, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Relationship of Institutional Size to Quality of Care: A Review of the Literature by David Balla, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Toward Reducing Recidivism in Foster Care by Norman. M. Block, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Institutions for Dependent and Neglected Children: Therapeutic Option of Choice or Last Resort by Malcolm Bush, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Specific Objectives for the Institutional Treatment of Juveniles by Dean Edwards (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Institution is not a Dirty Word by Fern Kupfer, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Humanizing the Detention Setting by Thomas Hughes (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Rights of Juveniles Confined in Training Schools, Crime and Delinquency by James D. Silbert and Alan Sussman, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Group Care for Children: Guidelines for Planning by James Whittaker, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Revitalizing Residential Settings, Martin Wolins (handwritten notes), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Effective Planning for Children in Institutional Settings by Paul Gitelson and Michael Stein, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- American Association for Protecting Children, Notes from the Denver Conference, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Institutional Self-Assessment by Andrea Mooney and Paul Gitelson, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- In Out of Home Care (IOHC), State Central Register Training Materials, New York State Resources, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Training for the State Central Register, Topic I, II and III (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Physical Evidence in Investigations, Basic Principles (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Interviewing Children, Basic Principles (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Written Statements, Basic Principles (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Effective Written Communications for Audit and Control Staff, Fraud and Abuse Investigators, Department of Social Services, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Positive Approaches to Discipline for Direct Care Workers, Protecting the Child in Residential Group Care, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Non-Physical Crisis Intervention Techniques (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Inappropriate Isolation and Restraint (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Investigation of Abuse or Neglect, Group Activities (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Possible Situations of Abuse and Neglect, Test Booklet (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Post Intake, Regional Breakdown of New York State State Central Register Staff, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Writing Samples of Institutional Abuse Investigators, Memorandum, New York State Department of Social Services, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Determinations 10/86-3/8, Institutional Abuse Reports, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Practice Exchange On Punishment, Edited by James Whittaker, Child Care Quarterly Volume 5 (4), Winter, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Intervention Style Survey by B.H.Arbes, The 1972 Annual Handbook for Group Facilitators, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- "Plain Talk" About Dealing with the Angry Child, National Institute of Mental Health, Division of Scientific and Public Information, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- The Need for Self Awareness in Child Care Work By Steve Young, Child Care Work in Focus, Volume 2 and 3, Summer and Fall, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- New Jersey Division of Youth and Family Services Curriculum (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Crisis Lecture, Child Protective Services (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Correspondence on the Isolation and Restraint curriculum, New York State Department of Social Services, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- R.A.I.R Participant's Outline; Appendix II, III and IV (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Video Performance Agreement and Release Forms, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Strategies for Serving Families with Children in Residential Treatment, The Children's Village, Spring Symposium, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Statewide Teamwork for Abused Runaways (STAR) Buddy Training System, Resource Manual, Draft, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Literature Review by Nancy Dodge-Reyome, Nancy Fritsche, Jane Powers, Andrea Mooney, and Michael Nunno, Child Protective Services Training Institute Institutional Abuse Prevention Symposium, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Staff Recruitment and Retention: A Working Paper (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Staff Supervision and the Prevention of Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Organization (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Professionalism and the prevention of Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Flowchart of Administartion, New York State Department of Social Services, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, Orientation and Course Schedule (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Original IAB Proposal, FCS Crisis Intervention in Residential Settings (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Affirmative Action Correspondence, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Emotional Maltreatment Curriculum, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Curriculum Advisory Committee Correspondence, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- New York State Conference on Child Abuse and Neglect, The Seconf Decade of Leadership, Albany, NY, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Resources for Youth Programs, Prepared by Margo Hittleman, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Family Life Development Center Memos, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Disclosing Sexual Abuse: The Impact of Developmental Variables by Mary DeYoung, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Child Molesters: A Behavioral Analysis For Law-Enforcement Officers Investigating Cases of Child Sexual Exploitation, National Center for Missing and Exploited Children in cooperation with the FBI, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- The Connection, Volume X, Issue I, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- The Connection, Volume X, Issue 2, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Escape, Preventing Child Abuse in the Harvest, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Independent Living Skills: Developing Resourcefulness Among Adolescents, Family Life Development Center Conference, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Protecting Children from the Maltreatment after Residential Placement: The Impact of the Recent Social Reform Movement and its Aftermath by George Thomas, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Addressing the Issue of Institutional Abuse and Neglect: An Overview by George Thomas (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Institutional; Child Abuse and Neglect and the Role of Child Protective Services by George Thomas (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Residential Child Maltreatment: An Unrecognized Problem in the United States by George Thomas (Box 5, Folder 15)
- FLDC Suggested Readings, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Outline of Training for Module One (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Juvenile and Child Welfare, Law Reporter, ABA, Volume 6, No.12, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Psychological Disorders Among Foster Children by Anna McIntyre and Thomas Keesler, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Substantiation of Child Abuse and Neglect by John Eckenrode, Jane Powers, John Doris, Joyce Munsch and Niall Bolger, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- A Study to Define and Assess Severity of Institutional Abuse/Neglect by Joel Rabb and Nolan Rindfleisch, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Toward an Operational Definition of Institutional Abuse/Neglect: A Study of Assessed Severity of Institutional Abuse/Neglect by Joel Rabb and Nolan Rindfleisch for Presentation at the Fourth International Conference on Child Abuse and Neglect, Paris, France, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- I CA/N: Make a Difference, Preventing Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect in Residential Care, A Symposium, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- New Jersey, Division of Youth and Family Services, Institutional Abuse and Neglect: A Training Guide for Child Care Staff in Residential Institutions, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- California, Department of Social Services, General Licensing Requirements, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Puerto Rico, Department of Social Services,General Licensing Requirements, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Puerto Rico, Institutional Abuse/Neglect, State Statutes Related to Child Abuse and Neglect, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Puerto Rico,Manual de Normas y Procedimientos para Los Servicios del Programa de Servicios a Familias con Ninos (in Spanish), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- In Out of Home Care (IOHC), Guidebook (Box 5, Folder 18)
- In Out of Home Care (IOHC), Activities (Box 5, Folder 19)
- New York State Commission on Quality of Care for the Mentally Disabled, Annual Report, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Berkshire Farm Center and Services for Youth, Statement of Philosophy and Policy with Reference to Discipline and Restraint, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Leake and Watts Children's Home, Policy on Restraint for Children Under the Agency's Care, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Hillside Children's Center, Policies Pertaining to Discipline (Box 5, Folder 20)
- The House of The Good Shepherd, Management of Acute Physical Behavior (Box 5, Folder 20)
- The Children's Home of Kingston, Restraint Policy, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- St. Joseph's Villa, Physical Restraint Policy and Method (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Policy on Clinical Restraint and Isolation, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Aggressive/Destructive Behaviors: A Focus on Treatment, Temple University Conference, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Strategies for Crisis Prevention/Intervention, Temple University Conference, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- The Law and the Use of Behavior Modification Practices, Thomas Covall (handwritten notes), Temple University Conference, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Psychiatric and Behavioral Disorders in the DD/MR Population by Lincoln Clark, Temple University Conference, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect: A Training Guide for Child Care Staff in Residential Institutions, Institutional Child Abuse Project, New Jersey Division of Youth and Family Services, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect: A Guide for Investigators by Gregory Smiles, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Legal Aspects of Residential Child (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Nonviolent Crisis Intervention Instructor Certification Program, National Crisis Prevention Institute, Workshop Manual (Box 5, Folder 22)
- International Learning Exchange in Professional Youthwork (ILEX), Workshop Manual, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- The Teaching Conference: Teaching Family Innnovation To Help Children Learn New Life Skills, Workshop Manual, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Managing for Excellence in Children, Youth and Family Services, The Child Welfare Institute, Workshop Manual, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Center for Foster and Residential Care, Program Summary, The Child Welfare Institute (Box 5, Folder 22)
- International Learning Exchange (ILEX) Year, Orientation, University of Connecticut, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Working with Families of Children in Residential Treatment by Celia Littauer, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Module IV, Manual (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Activity #8: The Mystery Game (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Assessing Professional Child Care Practice in the United States: Results of a National Survey of Skills and Job Tasks by Richard Small and Gary Carman, Presented at 12th Annual National Association of Homes for Children Conference, Denver, Colorado, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Investigating Child Abuse in Residential Care Settings by Jim Docherty (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Trigger Stories: Preventing Institutional Abuse through the Development of Positive Norms for Staff (Box 5, Folder 23)
- How do you deal with Conflict? Questionnaire (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Investigation In Out of Home Care, Instructors' Manual A, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Investigation In Out of Home Care, Instructors' Manual B, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Interviewing Child Victims, Guidelines for Criminal Justice System Personnel (Box 5, Folder 25)
- The Sexually Abused Boy by Alexander Zaphiris, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Study Lifts Doom from Sex Abuse, Daily News, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Child Sexual Abuse: Some Preliminary Considerations by Patrick Tooman (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Reporting Sexual Abuse, Maltreatment and Exploitation in Children, New York State Department of Social Services, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Child Protective Service Relationship to Law Enforcement (Box 5, Folder 25)